<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Austin Real Estate Video Blog with Brandi Adkins</title>
    <description>Our mission at Adkins Real Estate Group is to be your best resource for Austin real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Adkins Real Estate Group, your professional Austin Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 16:32:29 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 16:32:29 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buyers: Are You Following the 10 Commandments?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xrYBJcVdKYQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Treat these &quot;10 Commandments&quot; like scripture when you&amp;rsquo;re purchasing a home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m consulting with a buyer, no matter if it’s their first or fifth home purchase, I’m always sure to go over the process and costs involved in great detail. Most important of all, I go over the “10 Commandments” of buying a home. I understand no one likes to be preached at, but these are homebuyer musts as you move through the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, thou shall not:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Change jobs or become self-employed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Buy a new vehicle.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Use credit cards to excess or let your accounts fall behind.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Use money specifically reserved for closing costs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Omit financial debts or liabilities from your loan application.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There’s so much to learn when making a home purchase.%20http://localhost:4000/buyers-are-you-following-the-10-commandments.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There’s so much to learn when making a home purchase.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Buy furniture (even if payments are deferred until after closing).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Allow additional credit inquiries (except for insurance purposes).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Make large deposits without first checking with your loan officer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Change, open, or close any bank accounts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Cosign on a loan no matter who it’s for.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s so much to learn when making a home purchase. It’s so important to negotiate from strength and purchase with confidence. At Adkins Real Estate, we want you to love where you live because we understand there’s no place like home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the buying process (or if you’ve broken a commandment), you had better confess to your lender or my team and I straight away. We’d be happy to help however we can!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buyers-are-you-following-the-10-commandments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buyers-are-you-following-the-10-commandments.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can You Profit From the Fastest-Growing Trend in Real Estate?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HMlVDTHj_nc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Could you profit from the fastest-growing trend in real estate? Today I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how you can.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the fastest-growing trend in real estate today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a recent article from CNBC, it’s the build-to-rent movement. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more home builders are now building single-family homes specifically so they can rent them out. Last year, about 43,000 single-family homes were built for rent—the largest number in 40 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes good sense for several reasons:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Rents are increasing nationwide&lt;/strong&gt;. Home prices grew 2.7% this year. While this is a respectable number, it’s also the weakest increase in seven years. On the other hand, rent is surging and grew 3.2% nationwide year over year. In other words, rents currently offer some of the best returns on investment in real estate.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Demand for single-family homes is growing like crazy&lt;/strong&gt;. More and more renters may prefer to raise a family or live in a single-family home versus an apartment complex or community or building. The increase in both single-family home sales—as well as the growth in rent—is proof that this is a good investment.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. It’s an investment that can pay for itself within seven to 10 years&lt;/strong&gt;. The math for build-to-rent homes is simple: For investors who hold these properties even for just seven years, the residual cash flow could be worth more than the sale one time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Last year, about 43,000 single-family homes were built for rent—the largest number in 40 years.%20http://localhost:4000/can-you-profit-from-the-fastest-growing-trend-in-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Last year, about 43,000 single-family homes were built for rent—the largest number in 40 years.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These reasons explain why big builders and investors are so keen on “build to rent” right now, but is there a way you could benefit from the same underlying market conditions, too?&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Well, &lt;strong&gt;one smart option is to invest in a single-family home yourself and then rent it out&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;This might make a lot of sense in the current market for two big reasons:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;mortgage rates are at a temporary dip right now&lt;/strong&gt; and are near their all-time lows.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;In other words, &lt;strong&gt;it’s simply more affordable to buy a home right now&lt;/strong&gt;, because the interest payments at current rates would be so much lower than if you bought even six months ago.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The other good reason is that several affordable and attractive single-family homes have recently come onto our area market. In my opinion, they would make an excellent choice as an investment property.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;If you would like to see the homes I have in mind or if you have any questions in general, please reach out to me. I’d be glad to share my list with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/can-you-profit-from-the-fastest-growing-trend-in-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/can-you-profit-from-the-fastest-growing-trend-in-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Should You React to “Coming Soon” Listings?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LmnOnUGpIfI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a three-step process you should follow if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in a &amp;ldquo;coming soon&amp;rdquo; listing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s certainly smart marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m talking about those “coming soon” signs you’ve probably seen in at least a few front yards in our area. I frequently have homebuyers who are curious and interested in these listings, so I decided to answer a few questions about them and give you my perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, a “coming soon” home &lt;strong&gt;may or may not be listed on the MLS&lt;/strong&gt;. Either way, it will not yet be available for viewing. This might be because the home itself is not yet ready, or because the owners are in the process of moving out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I say it’s not available for viewing, that’s a hard &lt;u&gt;no&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. As long as this is a legitimate “coming soon” listing that complies with regulations, the home is off-limits to you or any other buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what should you do in case you spot a dream home which is “coming soon” but is not on the market yet? Well, here’s the three-step process I recommend to my clients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Beware your excitement&lt;/strong&gt;. Lots of folks, myself included, tend to want something more when it’s currently off-limits. Keep this in mind while evaluating a “coming soon” home, and separate what you think about this home from the alluring fact that it’s currently unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Do your research&lt;/strong&gt;. Even while a home is unavailable for viewing, you can gather a lot of information about it, including its sales history, old pictures if the home was previously listed on the MLS, and (if the home was previously listed on the MLS) of course, the date on which the listing will go live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. If it makes sense, make an early offer&lt;/strong&gt;. Even though a home is not yet available for viewing, you can still make an offer during this period. When submitting an offer on a home sight unseen, make sure you carefully craft the contract terms, including deadlines and contingencies, to minimize the risk you’re exposed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As long as this is a legitimate 'coming soon' listing that complies with regulations, the home is off-limits to you or any other buyers.%20http://localhost:4000/how-should-you-react-to-coming-soon-listings.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“As long as this is a legitimate ‘coming soon’ listing that complies with regulations, the home is off-limits to you or any other buyers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do decide to submit an early offer, don’t be surprised if it’s not accepted right away. Even with a fair offer, the sellers will likely want to see what kind of interest their home will get after it’s fully listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in buying mode and you want to see some of the great homes that are on the market right now and available for viewing (and not just coming soon), &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://maxavenue.com/maximum-value-system/buying-system/&quot;&gt;check out my website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you do come across a “coming soon” listing and you want to research more about it, give me a call. I have my finger on the pulse of Williamson County, and I can help you dig up all sorts of relevant info if you are considering such a home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, we want you to love where you live because there’s no place like home. If you have any other questions I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me as well. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-should-you-react-to-coming-soon-listings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-should-you-react-to-coming-soon-listings.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Are Interest Rates and Where Are They Going?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/82k95un91qA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interest rates are the lowest they’ve been in the last two months, but are home prices still high? Are they going up? &lt;strong&gt;I’m going to answer both of these questions today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, rates are at an average of 4.73%. At the beginning of November, that average was closer to 5.05%. That’s a change of around $70 per month on a monthly mortgage payment in our area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over the last two years, the housing shortage we’ve experienced has pushed up prices much higher than they should have gone.&lt;/strong&gt; When you couple that with rising rates, it really pushed potential buyers to their limits. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Although home prices are gaining, those gains are shrinking.%20http://localhost:4000/where-are-interest-rates-and-where-are-they-going.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Although home prices are gaining, those gains are shrinking.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So although home prices are high and are gaining, you should also know that the gains are shrinking. More homes are coming on the market, so if rates can stay low, we’ll see more buyers coming into the market. This bodes well for our market’s future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the current market or about real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 11:59:48 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/where-are-interest-rates-and-where-are-they-going.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/where-are-interest-rates-and-where-are-they-going.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why It’s Important to Price Your Home Effectively When Selling</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VLvaN6wmlFI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be easy to think your home is worth more than it actually is—after all, you’re proud of your home and you know buyers will love it just like you do! Unfortunately, &lt;strong&gt;this does not translate well to the market&lt;/strong&gt;, and overpriced homes tend to sit, unsold, until price reductions are made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This recently happened when a client and I made an offer on a home that had been sitting on the market for 47 days. It took a little bit—we had to get with the lender, talk pricing, etc., and by the time we made our offer, there were two other offers, as well. &lt;strong&gt;Why were there suddenly multiple offers after 47 days?&lt;/strong&gt; The home had a reduction that put it in line with neighborhood prices. Before, it had been $14,000 higher than comparable homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Overpriced homes tend to sit, unsold, until price reductions are made.%20http://localhost:4000/why-its-important-to-price-your-home-effectively-when-selling.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Overpriced homes tend to sit, unsold, until price reductions are made.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When the price became appropriate, the buyers came.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sellers, you can enjoy bidding wars from the outset if you simply price your home correctly. Buyers, don’t write off a home that’s overpriced—wait for the eventual price reductions that are bound to happen. When it matches the price of comparable homes, make sure you have everything lined up so that you’re ready to pounce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy or sell, have any questions, or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 14:48:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-its-important-to-price-your-home-effectively-when-selling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-its-important-to-price-your-home-effectively-when-selling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Make Preparations Now to Meet Your Real Estate Goals Later</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mSjOna1Bc50?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we wrap up 2018 and begin to set our sights on the new year ahead, planning for changes already underway, or soon-to-be underway, is so important—I like to consider it “assessing the situation.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe your family is outgrowing your home, you have children going off to college or relatives moving in, or it’s time to sell a property you no longer wish to maintain. Whatever the reason may be, &lt;strong&gt;now is the time to prepare. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Being prepared means having a blueprint for when that moment comes.%20http://localhost:4000/make-preparations-now-to-meet-your-real-estate-goals-later.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Being prepared means having a blueprint for when that moment comes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be that you’re looking forward to making an earnest offer on a home that’s right for you as soon as it hits the market. &lt;strong&gt;Being prepared means having a blueprint for when that moment comes&lt;/strong&gt;—having the approval in place, knowing average days on market for the area, and what you’ll net to roll into the next house would all be part of that blueprint. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life-changing (and life-defining) decisions such as this require proper preparation, so be prepared and in the know sooner rather than later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m here to help you prepare for these most critical real estate decisions. If you have any questions or need guidance in preparing for the future, please give me a call!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 15:59:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/make-preparations-now-to-meet-your-real-estate-goals-later.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/make-preparations-now-to-meet-your-real-estate-goals-later.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HOUSING MARKET UPDATES</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.simplifyingthemarket.com/?a=360843-5a01dae6d4383ad4df8857368ad6a851&amp;amp;iframe&quot; scrolling=&quot;yes&quot; frameborder=&quot;1&quot; marginheight=&quot;0px&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0px&quot; height=&quot;800px&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/housing-market-updates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/housing-market-updates.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Adkins Real Estate Group</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SFaeVqeXgmE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 14:53:08 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-adkins-real-estate-group.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-adkins-real-estate-group.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet Adkins Real Estate Group</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hb01txW2GN0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 14:50:56 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/meet-adkins-real-estate-group.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/meet-adkins-real-estate-group.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Things Homeowners Are Thankful For</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts&quot; src=&quot;https://www.simplifyingthemarket.com/en/videos/embed/360843-5a01dae6d4383ad4df8857368ad6a851/5bef1621&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 14:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-things-homeowners-are-thankful-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-things-homeowners-are-thankful-for.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
